Qunliang Xing

37 Xueyuan Road Haidian District, Beijing, China ryanxingql@gmail.com https://ryanxingql.github.io

Introduction

Qunliang Xing is a Ph.D. student at Beihang University, advised by Changjiang Distinguished Professor Mai Xu. He obtained his BEng and Honors degrees at Beihang University in 2019. His research interests include image/video enhancement and coding. He has published several papers in IEEE TPAMI and ECCV, and one of them is top 1% highly cited according to the Essential Science Indicators (ESI). His papers have received over 300 citations. He has won two NTIRE championships. His open-source projects have received more than 600 stars. He was selected for the Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program. He is awarded the OpenMMLab Active Contributor. He serves as a reviewer for five IEEE transactions and conferences. He also excels in sports, having won second place in the Beihang 100m final and the Beihang soccer championship as the school team captain.

Education

Beihang University	2019.9 – Present
Ph.D. student	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Ph.D. Student	Shen Yuan Honors College
Beihang University	2015.9 - 2019.7
Bachelor of Engineering	School of Electronics and Information Engineering
Honors Bachelor	Shen Yuan Honors College

Publications

[1] DAQE: Enhancing the Quality of Compressed Images by Exploiting the Inherent Characteristic of Defocus

Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Xin Deng, Yichen Guo

IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2023)

[2] Progressive Training of a Two-stage Framework for Video Restoration Qunliang Xing, Meisong Zheng, Minglang Qiao, Mai Xu, Lai Jiang, Huaida Liu, Ying Chen IEEE/CVF Computer Vision and Pattern Recognition (CVPR) Workshops (2022) Technical report of our winning method in the NTIRE challenge.

[3] DeepQTMT: A Deep Learning Approach for Fast QTMT-based CU Partition of Intra-mode VVC

Tianyi Li, Mai Xu, Runzhi Tang, Ying Chen, Qunliang Xing IEEE Transactions on Image Processing (2021)

[4] Early Exit or Not: Resource-efficient Blind Quality Enhancement for Compressed Images Qunliang Xing, Mai Xu, Tianyi Li, Zhenyu Guan European Conference on Computer Vision (2020)

[5] MFQE 2.0: A New Approach for Multi-frame Quality Enhancement on Compressed Video Qunliang Xing, Zhenyu Guan, Mai Xu, Ren Yang, Tie Liu, Zulin Wang IEEE Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence (2019) Highly cited paper (Top 1%) by Essential Science Indicators (ESI).

Work Experience

Research Intern on Video Quality Enhancement Tao Technology, Alibaba Group	2021.12 – Present
Tencent Rhino-bird Open-source Training Program Tencent Open Source	2021.7 - 2021.9
Reviewer IEEE TIP/TMM/TCSVT/JAS/ICME	2021.2 – Present
Research Intern on Video Quality Enhancement for HW265 Codec 2012 Lab, Huawei	2018.12 - 2019.12

H

Beihang Excellent Academic Fund for Ph.D. Candidates	2023
Beihang University	Ranked 1st in the college.
Glarun Scholarship	2022
The 14TH Research Institute, CETC	Among the 4 awardees in the college.
Winner of the NTIRE Challenge on Video Quality Enhance NTIRE Challenge @ CVPR	ment 2022 Ranked 1st among the 8 finalists.
Beihang Excellent Graduate	2019
Beihang University	Top 20% in the university.
Beihang Outstanding/Merit Student	2015/18/21/22
Beihang University	Top 5% in the university.
Shenzhen Merit Student	2014
Education Bureau of Shenzhen Municipality	Sole awardee in the school.